<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Handl3r&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Handl3r&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020, ThaiBuiXuan</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 03:34:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aws Account and Organization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/aws-account-and-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 03:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/aws-account-and-organization/</guid>
      <description>AWS Account and AWS Organization What inside of this post? Explain about AWS Account and setup a account with MFA setup. Explain about AWS Organization and setup an Organization with a general account and a prod and fly(development) account. It will be like a real AWS Organization in a company. Explain about SCP and make an example demonstrates about it. Understand how an administrator managements permission of each AWS account in in a company.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Basic_accounting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/basic_accounting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 14:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/basic_accounting/</guid>
      <description>Basic accounting topic A story that related to accounting basic Joe Perez(JP) start a business: a parcel delivery service in his community. He start by run a company Direct Delivery, Inc.(DDI) JP is not have knowledge about accounting so he have advisor Marilyn(M). So M thinks DDI can have thousands of transaction each year -&amp;gt; Accounting software is needed.&#xA;Some transactions like:&#xA;Joe will no doubt start his business by putting some of his own personal money into it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Note_concurrency_golang</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/note_concurrency_golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 15:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/note_concurrency_golang/</guid>
      <description>&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-Noteeeeeeeee&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&#xA;Os schedualer mechanics&#xA;các process tương tự như container, chứa các context cần thiết cho chương trình chạy.các process chạy thực chất chính là các pe của nó chạy. path execution là 1 đơn vị thực thi. Ví dụ như 1 instruction mã máy chẳng hạn. Điều này còn phụ thuộc vào mức độ trừu tượng mà ta muốn. Os schedualer quan tâm đến các path execution này. Ví dụ 1 core cần chạy 10000 path execution thì nó sẽ phải tính toán cho mỗi path execution 1 slice of time trên core đó.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab Jenkins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lab_jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 13:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lab_jenkins/</guid>
      <description>*** Dựng lab chơi chơi chạy jenkins nào *** Ai chưa biết về CI/CD thì tìm hiểu trước đi nhé.&#xA;Mô tả lab cơ bản như sau: Project là 1 con web cơ bản viết bằng golang cần được test và deploy liên tục lên server thông qua jenkins. SCM là github. Link repo https://github.com/handl3r/multibranches Server deploy dùng docker hay máy ảo cũng được. Mình dùng ubuntu server chạy bằng virtualbox.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Golang Ultimate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/golang-ultimate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 17:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/golang-ultimate/</guid>
      <description>*** Đây là draft nhá :3 ***&#xA;*****Đây là những thứ mình note lại khi học khóa ultimateGo của William Kennedy&#xA;Lesson 1. Go có cách riêng của nó. Code phải đơn giản và có nghĩa, dễ đọc. 2 mục tiêu chính: code(kiến trúc) đơn giản, có nghĩa tránh chi phí ẩn trong các mẩu code nhỏ. Luôn giữ trong đầu sự tổng quan của hệ thống đơn giản. Lesson 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/next-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 03:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/next-time/</guid>
      <description>**Of course, this is draft ***&#xA;This is notification for plans: Maybe next week, i will publish my second draft which i wrote when i learned apart of Ultimate-Go course. And, maybe it will become with english-mystupidenglish. In future, i want to deep into docker, virtualization. It can be building backend for web server, run it in containers and use prometheus for monitoring. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Golang Scratch Paper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/golang-scratch-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 16:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/golang-scratch-paper/</guid>
      <description>*** Đây là draft nhá :3 ***&#xA;Khai báo biến trong golang Khai báo chuẩn bằng từ khóa var và có thể kèm theo initializer: var( x int y int = 2 z = &amp;#34;x&amp;#34; ) Biến có thể định kiểu cụ thể. Nếu không thì nó sẽ được định kiểu với giá trị truyền vào hàm khởi tạo cho nó( = ), nếu không có giá trị khởi tạo thì giá trị mặc định là zezo value</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 17:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Handl3r Bring my code to the real-world&#xA;Fullname: ThaiBuiXuan&#xA;Updating&amp;hellip;&#xA;Age: 24 Job: Software Engineer Main Languages: Golang, Ruby Techs: Golang, Ruby, Rails, Gin, SQL-database(Mysql, Firebird,&amp;hellip;), NoSQL-database(mongodb), Virtualization(docker), CI/CD(CircleCI)&#xA;Knowledge: Software development, Cryptography, Cyber Security,&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 17:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Hello, this’s my blog </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
